?Are you ready kids-
？你们准​​备好了吗孩子们-
!CHILDREN: Aye-aye, Captain
！孩子们：是啊，船长
.I can't hear you-
.我听不到你说话-
!CHILDREN: Aye-aye, Captain
！孩子们：是啊，船长
--Oh-
- 哦-
THEME SONG: Who lives in
?a pineapple under the sea
？海底的菠萝
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
Absorbent and yellow
!and porous is he
吸水性和黄色
！他是多孔的
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
If nautical nonsense
--be something you wish
如果航海废话
--成为你想要的东西
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
Then drop on the deck
!and flop like a fish
然后落在甲板上
！然后像鱼一样扑通扑通
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
?Ready
？准备好
,SpongeBob SquarePants
,海绵宝宝
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
!SpongeBob SquarePants
!海绵宝宝
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
NARRATOR: Welcome to Bikini
Bottom, where can be found some
旁白：欢迎来到比基尼
底下，哪里可以找到一些
of the finest specimens
.of undersea life
最好的标本
.海底生物
.Well, you know
.嗯，你知道
?An award-
?一个奖项-
!I never got an award before
！我以前从未获得过奖项
!Look, rock
！看，摇滚
!I got an award
！我获奖了
!Jellyfish, I got an award
！水母，我获奖了
--Island, I got an awa
——岛屿，我得到了阿瓦
[GASP]
[喘气]
.I gotta show SpongeBob
.我要给海绵宝宝看
.Hold still, Gary-
.别动，加里-
.Almost done
.快完成了
?Hey, SpongeBob, guess what-
？嘿，海绵宝宝，你猜怎么着-
!I got an award
！我获奖了
.That's great, Patrick-
.那太好了，帕特里克-
?What's it for
?它有什么用
.See for yourself-
.亲自看看-
For outstanding-
--achievement in achievement
对于杰出的——
——成就中的成就
.SpongeBob SquarePants
.海绵宝宝
?SpongeBob SquarePants-
?海绵宝宝-
That's a funny way
.to spell my name
这是一个有趣的方式
.拼写我的名字
Patrick, I think-
.the award is for me
帕特里克，我想——
.这个奖项是属于我的
.You must have got it by mistake
.一定是你弄错了
.But it's shiny-
.但它很闪亮-
.Yeah-
。是的-
?But you know what else is shiny
？但你知道还有什么是闪亮的
!Ice cream-
！冰淇淋-
!Exactly-
！确切地-
!I can find it-
！我能找到它-
?Is it in here
？在这儿吗
No, don't, that's-
.my-- award closet
不，不要，那是——
.my--奖品柜
!I want an award-
！我想要一个奖品-
.Aw, Patrick, don't cry-
.噢，帕特里克，别哭-
.You'll get an award one day
.总有一天你会获得奖励
I'm never gonna get-
an award, because I've
我永远不会得到-
一个奖项，因为我已经
.never done anything
.从未做过任何事
!But you're Patrick-- Star-
！但你是帕特里克——明星——
.You can do anything you want
.你可以做任何你想做的事
.That's easy for you to say-
.这对你来说很容易说-
.You're SpongeBob
.你是海绵宝宝
Patrick, if you-
,want to win an award
帕特里克，如果你——
,想要获奖
.you have to do something
.你必须做点什么
.Hm-
.嗯-
I want to defeat
the giant monkey man
我想打败
巨型猴人
!and save the ninth dimension
!并保存第九维
!Me too-
！我也是-
.But that sounds a little hard
.但这听起来有点难
?Why don't we start smaller
？我们为什么不从小事做起
I wanna defeat the-
little monkey man
我想打败——
小猴人
!and save the eighth dimension
！并保存第八维
.Smaller-
.较小-
.Doctor-
。医生-
.Smaller-
.较小-
?Fireman-
？消防队员-
.The smallest you can think of-
.你能想到的最小的-
?A job at the Krusty Krab-
?在蟹堡王的一份工作-
!Yeah-
！是的-
I do things at
.work all the time
我做事在
.一直工作
!Then let's go-
！那么我们走吧——
Boy, it was sure nice of
.Mr. Krabs to give me a job
男孩，这确实很好
.先生。蟹蟹给我一份工作
.And at $50 an hour, too-
.而且每小时 50 美元-
When I started
working here, I had
当我开始的时候
在这里工作，我有
.to pay Mr. Krabs $100 an hour
.支付蟹蟹先生每小时 100 美元
.Hey, Squidward
.嘿，章鱼哥
?Guess who just got a job
？猜猜谁刚刚找到工作
?Guess who just quit-
？猜猜谁刚刚退出-
?Do I get my award yet-
？我拿到奖了吗-
You have to work-
?for it, remember
你必须工作——
？为此，请记住
.Tartar sauce-
.塔塔酱-
.Pick up order-
.取货订单-
?Do I get my award now-
？我现在可以领奖了吗-
.No-
。不-
You have to take the
.tray to the customer
你必须采取
.托盘给顾客
[BURP]
[打嗝]
.Almost
。几乎
.Try again
.再试一次
And this time, make sure
.the food gets to the table
这一次，请确保
.食物到达餐桌
?Like that-
？就这样-
.Nope-
。没有-
!Barnacles-
！藤壶-
.Let's try something different-
.让我们尝试一些不同的东西-
All you have to do
.is answer the phone
所有你需要做的
.正在接电话
.Aye-aye, captain-
.耶-耶，船长-
MAN ON PHONE: Is
?this the Krusty Krab
电话里的男人：是
？这是蟹堡王
.No, this is Patrick-
.不，这是帕特里克-
MAN ON PHONE: Is
?this the Krusty Krab
电话里的男人：是
？这是蟹堡王
.No, this is Patrick-
.不，这是帕特里克-
MAN ON PHONE: Is
?this the Krusty Krab
电话里的男人：是
？这是蟹堡王
!No-
！不-
!This is Patrick
！这是帕特里克
.I am not a Krusty Krab
.我不是蟹堡王
Patrick, that's the-
.name of the restaurant
帕特里克，那就是——
.餐厅名称
!Fish paste-
！鱼酱-
It looks a little dusty-
.around table three
看起来有点灰尘～
.围绕表三
?How about if you sweep it out
？如果你把它扫掉怎么样？
?What's the point-
？有什么意义-
.I can't do anything right
.我什么都做不好
.You'll do fine-
.你会做得很好-
.Hey, pal-
.嘿，朋友-
You just blow in
?from stupid town
你只要吹进去
？来自愚蠢的小镇
.Keep trying, Patrick-
.继续努力，帕特里克-
I got a load of awards-
.for SpongeBob SquarePants
我获得了很多奖项——
.海绵宝宝
?Why can't I do anything right-
？为什么我不能做任何正确的事-
!Gah
！嘎
.Kitchen-
。厨房-
I'm never gonna-
.get an award now
我永远不会-
.立即获得奖励
.Don't give up, Patrick-
.不要放弃，帕特里克-
This time I've got
.something I know you can do
这次我有
.我知道你可以做的事
.We're gonna open a jar
.我们要打开一个罐子
.Easy
。简单的
.Now you try
.现在你试试
.First, get a jar
.首先，得到一个罐子
.Patrick, that's a pickle
.帕特里克，那是泡菜
.Yes-
。是的-
.You need a jar-
.你需要一个罐子-
.No
。不
.Try this
.试试这个
.Now, take the lid off the jar
.现在，打开罐子的盖子
.Just relax
.放松一下
.Lift your hand
.举起你的手
.Great
。伟大的
.We're almost there
.我们快到了
.Now put it on the lid
.现在把它放在盖子上
.No, the lid
.不，盖子
.The lid
.盖子
--The lid-- the lid
--the lid-- lid
--盖子--盖子
!lid-- lid-- lid-- lid-- freeze
!盖子--盖子--盖子--盖子--冻结
.Almost there
.快到了
.Now head for the lid
.现在前往盖子
.Cold
。寒冷的
.Warmer
.温暖
!Warmer
！更温暖
!You're hot
！你很热
!You're on fire
！你着火了
!Ow, it burns-
！噢，它燃烧了——
.OK, OK-
.好吧，好吧-
.Wait, wait
.等等，等等
.Do exactly as I do
.完全照我做的做
.Exactly as I do
.正如我所做的那样
--Exactly-- exactly-- exactly
——完全正确——完全正确——完全正确
.Exactly as you do-
.正如你所做的那样-
!Oh no, I broke it
！哦不，我把它弄坏了
!No, no, Patrick-
！不，不，帕特里克-
!You did it
！你做到了
?I did-
？我做了-
[CHEERING]
[欢呼]
!Touchdown
！接地
!I'm jar master
！我是罐子大师
!That was great, Patrick-
！太棒了，帕特里克-
.You really got the hang of it
.你真的掌握了窍门
.Yeah-
。是的-
Remember when I had my hand
?up and I put it on the lid
记得当我握着我的手
？向上，我把它放在盖子上
.Oh, yeah-
.哦，是的-
.And then I took the lid off-
.然后我把盖子打开-
!And I thought I broke it
！我以为我把它弄坏了
!Ha-
！哈-
.Yeah
。是的
!But I didn't-
！但我没有-
.I opened the jar with my hand
.我用手打开了罐子
And it was all because you
.showed me how to do it
而这一切都是因为你
.告诉我怎么做
.I'm never gonna forget this
.我永远不会忘记这一点
Patrick, you do-
,exactly what I do
帕特里克，你确实——
，正是我所做的
and you'll have an
.award in no time
你会得到一个
.立即获奖
[ROOSTER CROWING]
[公鸡报晓]
.I'm ready
.我准备好了
.Good morning, SpongeBob-
.早上好，海绵宝宝-
.Wow-
。哇-
It's amazing how a
simple change of clothes
令人惊奇的是如何
简单换衣服
can make a guy
.look-- just like me
可以造就一个男人
.看——就像我一样
!Yup-
！是的-
,If I'm gonna be an award-winner
.I've gotta dress like one
,如果我要成为获奖者
.我得穿得像个
.That's creepy-
.这太令人毛骨悚然了-
!But flattering
！但是很讨人喜欢
!I'm ready-
！我准备好了-
!I'm ready
！我准备好了
!I'm ready-
！我准备好了-
!I'm ready
！我准备好了
?Huh-
？哈-
.Well, back to the old grind
.好吧，回到老问题
.Well, back to the old grind-
.好吧，回到老问题-
.Forgot my hat-
.忘了我的帽子-
.Uh-- me too-
.呃--我也是-
!Whoa-
！哇-
But
但
.Dropped my spatula-
.我的锅铲掉了-
.Uh-- me too-
.呃--我也是-
!Ow
！噢
!Aha-
！啊哈-
!You're copying me
！你在抄袭我
.Yes-
。是的-
?Why are you doing that-
？你为什么要这么做-
So I can win an-
.award, like you
这样我就能赢得——
.奖，像你一样
.Well, it's annoying-
.嗯，这很烦人-
!So stop it
！所以停下来吧
.Stop it-
.别这样-
.Say, you're good-
.说吧，你很好-
.Thanks-
。谢谢-
!Ha-
！哈-
Ha-
哈-
.Darn-
.该死-
Mary had a little-
lamb, whose fleece
玛丽有一点——
羔羊，其羊毛
--was white as
!pickled fish lips
——白如
.Seaweevil
.海象虫
.Yorgie shmorgies
.约吉·什莫吉斯
SPONGEBOB (VOICEOVER): At
.least I'm safe inside my mind
海绵宝宝（画外音）：在
.至少我内心是安全的
PATRICK (VOICEOVER): At least
.I'm safe inside my mind
帕特里克（画外音）：至少
.我心里很安全
!Ahh-
！啊——
!Stop copying me-
！别再抄袭我了——
!There's the award for that-
！这就是奖励——
Well, I guess it's-
.safe to go in now
嗯，我猜是——
.现在可以安全进入
Patrick, how long are-
?you gonna keep this up
帕特里克，还有多久——
Until I have as-
!many awards as you
！和你一样获得许多奖项
!We'll see about that-
！我们会看看-
!No we won't-
！不，我们不会-
I'm the jump rope-
!champion of Bikini Bottom
我是跳绳——
！比基尼泳裤冠军
!Me too-
！我也是-
?Oh yeah-
？哦是的-
I call this one
!the slice and dice
我称这个为
!切片和切块
!Ha
！哈
!Not a scratch on me Wha
！我身上没有任何划痕哇
!Oh, no you don't-
！哦，不，你不-
!Ugh
！啊
Not much fun being-
?me now, huh, Patrick
没什么好玩的——
？现在是我了，帕特里克
?Are you kidding-
？你在开玩笑吧-
I used to do this way before
!I started copying you
我以前曾经这样做过
！我开始模仿你
!Whee
!呼
!My turn
！轮到我了
I wish I had the-
.old Patrick back
我希望我有-
.老帕特里克回来了
.But he just wants to be like me
.但他只是想像我一样
.Hi, I'm Patrick Star-
.嗨，我是帕特里克·斯塔-
I'm the laziest, pinkest
,starfish in Bikini Bottom
我最懒 最粉红
,比基尼泳裤中的海星
,and I wish I were me
.and not SpongeBob
，我希望我是我
.而不是海绵宝宝
What's so great about-
?being a big pink loser
有什么了不起的——
？成为一个大粉红失败者
.Exactly
。确切地
I was never closer to
an award than the minute
我从未如此接近过
比一分钟更重要的奖项
.I started copying you
.我开始模仿你
--But Patrick-
——但是帕特里克——
!Patrick's not here-
！帕特里克不在这里-
!Trophy delivery-
！奖杯递送-
?Another trophy-
？另一个奖杯-
!Oh, great-
！哦，太棒了-
?What's it for this time
？这次是为了什么呢？
For doing absolutely-
nothing longer than
为了绝对做到-
没有什么比
!anyone else-- Patrick
！还有其他人吗——帕特里克
!This trophy's for you
！这个奖杯是给你的
!Yay-
！耶-
?So, what are you gonna do now-
？那么，你现在要做什么-
!I'm gonna go protect my title-
！我要去保护我的头衔-
NARRATOR: So you thought
?I was kidding, huh
旁白：所以你以为
？我开玩笑的吧
No, in Bikini Bottom, excellence
.can be found even under a rock
不，穿着比基尼泳裤，卓越
.甚至可以在岩石下找到
NARRATOR: Every day is
,a holiday for SpongeBob
旁白：每一天都是
,海绵宝宝的假期
.even if he has to make one up
.即使他必须弥补
Hey, everybody, it's-
!Leif Erikson Day
嘿，大家好，这是——
!莱夫·埃里克森日
!Hinga dinga durgen
.Ahoy, Patrick
.嘿，帕特里克
!It's Leif Erikson Day
！今天是莱夫·埃里克森日
.There's a note
.有一个注释
,PATRICK (VOICEOVER): SpongeBob
.went to get more giant paper
帕特里克（画外音）：海绵宝宝
.去拿更多的巨纸
.Uh-- Patrick
.呃--帕特里克
!PS-- happy Leif Erikson Day
!PS——莱夫·埃里克森日快乐
!Yerger hernder dernger
!Yerger Hernder dernger
!耶尔格·赫恩德·德恩格
.Aw-
.噢-
.So much for that
.就这么多了
!Maybe Sandy will play with me
！也许桑迪会和我一起玩
.Another note
.另一个注释
,SANDY (VOICEOVER): SpongeBob
.went south for the winter
桑迪（画外音）：海绵宝宝
.去南方过冬
.Love, Sandy
.爱，桑迪
.I don't get it-
.我不明白-
.The water's fine
.水很好
!Hey, Squidward
！嘿，章鱼哥
?Wanna play
？要玩
.SQUIDWARD (VOICEOVER): No
.SQUIDWARD（画外音）：不
?Are you sure-
？你确定吗-
.SQUIDWARD (VOICEOVER): Yes
.SQUIDWARD（画外音）：是的
.Darn-
.该死-
I wish I had a
.buddy to play with
我希望我有一个
.一起玩的伙伴
.I know
。我知道
.I'll make one
.我来做一个
!Stuck buddy
！卡住了伙计
.Nah
.不
!Rock buddy
！摇滚伙伴
.Nope
。没有
!Sink buddy
！水槽伙计
.Almost
。几乎
.I've got it
.我明白了
!This-- is-- great
！这——这——太棒了
I can't wait for you to meet
.Squidward and Mr. Krabs
我等不及你见面了
.章鱼哥和蟹老板
.Don't be shy
.别害羞
!Come on
！快点
--Please, come again-
.when I'm not working
——请你再来吧——
.当我不工作的时候
.Next
。下一个
.Hi, Squidward-
.嗨，章鱼哥-
How am I supposed-
to enjoy your day off
我该怎么办-
享受你的休息日
?if you come to work anyway
？如果你还是来上班的话
I want you to meet my-
.new friend, Bubble Buddy
我想让你见见我的——
.新朋友，泡泡巴迪
?This bubble is your friend-
？这个泡泡是你的朋友-
!Haha
！哈哈
,Well, he's handsome
.I'll give him that
，嗯，他很帅
.我会给他那个
!Ha
！哈
?What'll it be
?会是什么
.Oh, I'm not hungry-
.哦，我不饿-
.Well, thanks for stopping by-
.嗯，谢谢你过来-
!Wait-
！等待-
You haven't taken Bubble
.Buddy's order yet
你还没拿过泡泡
.Buddy的订单还没到
?Why would I do that-
？我为什么要这么做-
.He's hungry-
.他饿了-
.He's an inanimate object-
.他是一个无生命的物体-
.his money's no good here
.他的钱在这里没用
,What are you saying-
?Mr. Squidward
?Mr.章鱼哥
.Everyone's money is good here
.这里每个人的钱都很好
,At the Krusty Krab
.we serves all kinds
,在蟹堡王
.我们提供各种服务
I'm not taking an-
.order for a bubble
我不会接受-
.订购泡沫
!Sure you are-
！当然你是-
Or I'll fill your life
.with misery and woe
或者我会填满你的生活
.带着痛苦和悲伤
.Even if you quit
.即使你放弃了
?May I take your order-
？我可以接受您的订单吗-
.Wait, Bubble Buddy-
.等等，泡泡伙伴-
.Let me decide for you
.让我替你决定
.Hm
.嗯
.Krabby Patty
.克拉比·帕蒂
.Double Patty Patty
.双帕蒂帕蒂
.Krabby Junior Junior
.Jumble Small Patty
.Jumble小帕蒂
.Junior Senior Sophomore Patty
.初中、高中二年级学生帕蒂
.Quarter Ouncer Double Pounder
.四分之一盎司双磅
!Ooh, it's all so good
！哦，一切都那么好
He'll just have
.one of everything
他只会有
.一切之一
?One of everything-
？一切之一-
!Whoopee
！哇喔
[BUZZING]
[嗡嗡声]
!I love Bubble Buddy
！我爱泡泡伙伴
Squidward, show our best
.customer to his table
章鱼哥，展现我们最好的一面
.顾客到他的餐桌
.Bubble Buddy's thirsty-
.泡泡巴迪渴了-
How about a glass of-
.our finest shampoo
来一杯怎么样——
.我们最好的洗发水
!Ha
！哈
!Ha ha
！哈哈
.Sounds great-
.听起来很棒-
.Oh-
。哦-
Here's your hair
.care product, sir
这是你的头发
.护理产品，先生
Uh, Bubble Buddy-
.likes bendy straws
呃，泡泡伙伴——
.喜欢弯曲的吸管
?Huh
？哈
?What's that
？那是什么
Bubble Buddy says
.it tastes funny
泡泡好友 说
.味道很有趣
?What do you think
？你怎么认为
!Mr. Krabs-
！先生。蟹蟹-
.Think of the customer-
.为客户着想-
.Oh, silly me-
.哦，愚蠢的我-
.I got the diet shampoo
.我买了减肥洗发水
.Here we go
。开始了
One of everything
.for Bubble Buddy
一切之一
.对于泡泡好友
!Oh, no, Squidward, wait-
！噢，不，章鱼哥，等等——
!There's cheese on these patties
！这些馅饼上有奶酪
?And-
？和-
Bubble Buddy's-
.lactose intolerant
泡泡好友的-
.乳糖不耐症
.He can't eat cheese
.他不能吃奶酪
?What should we do
?我们应该做什么
!We-
！我们-
How about you take
--these patties and sho
你拿怎么样
--这些馅饼和sho
!MR. KRABS: Mr. Squidward
！先生。螃蟹：章鱼哥先生
.Don't worry, Bubble Buddy-
.别担心，泡泡伙伴-
Squidward will
.make a fresh batch
章鱼哥将
.制作一批新鲜的
?What-
？什么-
?Is he allergic to bread, too
？他也对面包过敏吗
Actually, he doesn't-
.like the crust
事实上，他并不——
.像地壳一样
And Squidward, the ketchup
.should be under the patty
还有章鱼哥，番茄酱
.应该在肉饼下面
And Squidward, the pickles
.should be on the left side
还有章鱼哥，泡菜
.应该在左侧
And Squidward, you
--should-- and Squidward
还有章鱼哥，你
--应该--和章鱼哥
--and Squidward-- and Squidward
——和章鱼哥——和章鱼哥
!Here-
！这里-
.One of everything
.一切之一
,No cheese, no crust
,pickles to the left
,没有奶酪，没有外壳
,左边的泡菜
,four squirts of ketchup
,wheat buns, non-dairy lettuce
,四喷番茄酱
、小麦面包、非乳制生菜
and farm-raised
!tomatoes, carnival style
和农场饲养的
!西红柿，嘉年华风格
And, if there's
anything else I can
并且，如果有
我还能做什么
!do, please, hesitate to ask
！请犹豫一下再问吧
!That was delicious-
！真好吃-
.Money's on the table, Mr. Krabs
.蟹老板，钱已经摆在桌面上了
!So long, boys-
！再见，孩子们——
,You see, Squidward
the restaurant
，你看，章鱼哥
餐厅
.game is all about service
.game 就是服务
.The customer is always right
.顾客永远是对的
Remember that, lad, and you'll
.be as successful as me one day
记住这一点，小伙子，你就会
.有一天会像我一样成功
.Oh, you're right, Mr. Krabs-
.哦，你说得对，蟹老板-
.I learned my lesson
.我吸取了教训
And by the way, Bubble
.Buddy picked up the tab
顺便说一下，泡泡
.巴迪付了帐单
?What's this-
？这是什么-
!Bubble money-
！泡泡钱-
.At least they left a tip
.至少他们留下了小费
.Here we are, Bubble Buddy-
.我们来了，泡泡伙伴-
.Goo Lagoon
.古泻湖
There are lots of
.ways to have fun here
有很多
.在这里享受乐趣的方法
!Dudes, bury me-
！伙计们，埋葬我吧——
?See what I mean-
？明白我的意思-
.All done
.全部完成
!All right-
！好的-
Bubble Buddy, you dig him out-
.while I get some cotton candy
泡泡巴迪，你把他挖出来-
.当我拿到一些棉花糖时
.Don't just stand there, dude-
.别只是站在那里，伙计-
.The tide's coming in
.潮水来了
!Ha ha
！哈哈
?Dude
？伙计
.My friend's in there-
.我的朋友在那里-
.Congratulations-
.恭喜-
!Woo-
！呜——
!Shake it
！摇一摇
!Woo
！呜
!Shake it, yeah
！摇一摇，是的
!Shake that bubble butt
！摇晃那个泡泡屁股
!Yeah
！是的
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
!Oh, oh-
！噢，噢——
It's the world famous
.surf bum, Grubby Grouper
这是世界闻名的
.surf bum，Grubby 石斑鱼
.Later, Groupies-
.后来，追星族们-
Grubby's gotta go catch
.some gnarly pounders
格鲁比得去抓
.一些粗糙的磅锤
!Awoo
!阿宇
!Oh-
！哦-
I'll never wash
.this flipper again
我永远不会洗
.又是这个脚蹼
.Hey, Pearl-
.嘿，珍珠-
.Shake hands with Bubble Buddy
.与泡泡好友握手
--Wha-
- 世界卫生大会-
[SOBBING]
[抽泣]
.It's his first time on his own-
.这是他第一次独自-
.Once again, congratulations-
.再次恭喜-
.Popcorn, peanuts-
.爆米花，花生-
.Ice cold drinks-
.冰冷饮料-
!Two hours is long enough-
！两个小时足够长了——
!That's it
！就是这样
.Hey, Bubble Buddy-
.嘿，泡泡哥们-
.You're finished
.你已经完成了
He kept us waiting-
?for a bubble
他让我们久等了——
？为了一个泡沫
.That's nothing-
.那没什么-
!He called us fat
！他叫我们胖子
!He washed my flipper-
！他洗了我的脚​​蹼-
!He owes me money-
！他欠我钱——
He made me provide-
!excellent service
他让我提供——
！优质的服务
Dudes, he made me-
.experience high tide
伙计们，他让我——
.体验高潮
!Ha ha
！哈哈
He poisoned our water-
,supply, burned our crops
他在我们的水里下了毒——
，供应，烧毁了我们的庄稼
and delivered a plague
!onto our houses
并带来了一场瘟疫
！到我们的房子
?He did-
？他做了——
.No-
。不-
But are we just gonna
?wait around until he does
但我们只是要
？等他来
!I say we tip something over-
！我说我们把事情搞砸了-
!Yeah-
！是的-
!Hey-
！嘿-
?Now what-
？现在怎么办-
!Get the lifeguard-
！找救生员——
!Wait-
！等待-
Don't waste this
.senseless violence on him
不要浪费这个
.对他无意义的暴力
It's that stupid
bubble of SpongeBob's
就是这么蠢
海绵宝宝的泡泡
.that's causing all the problems
.这就是造成所有问题的原因
?Who's with me
?谁和我在一起
!Pop the bubble-
！戳破泡泡——
[SHOUTING]
[喊叫]
.Hey, everyone-
.嘿，大家-
Have you met my
?friend, Bubble Buddy
你遇见过我的
？朋友，泡泡好友
.Yes-
。是的-
Hey, is, uh-- one of-
?those sewing circles
嘿，是，呃——其中之一——
？那些缝纫圈
.No-
。不-
Would you mind not getting-
?so close with those pins
你介意不得到-
？离那些别针很近
Pointy objects make Bubble
.Buddy uncomfortable
尖尖的物体会产生气泡
.哥们不舒服
SpongeBob, that-
.bubble's gotta go
海绵宝宝，那个——
.bubble该走了
.Oh, no-
.哦，不-
.He already took care of that
.他已经处理好了
.But thanks for your concern
.不过谢谢你的关心
!Ahh-
！啊——
?Why
？为什么
You and that bubble have-
!been nothing but trouble
你和那个泡泡有——
！除了麻烦什么也没有
.It's time to end it
.是时候结束它了
!No-
！不-
!I won't let you
！我不会让你
!Here we go
！开始了
!You'll never catch us now
！你现在永远追不到我们了
!Never
！绝不
!Ha ha
！哈哈
!Never
！绝不
.Ne-- ver
。绝不
Enough seahorsing-
.around, SpongeBob
够海马了——
.周围，海绵宝宝
!Give us that bubble
！给我们那个泡沫
!Pop the bubble-
！戳破泡泡——
!Pop the bubble
！戳破泡泡
!No-
！不-
!You can't
！你不能
--He's not just a bubble
!he's a Bubble Buddy
——他不只是一个泡沫
！他是泡泡好友
.He's my friend and I love him
.他是我的朋友，我爱他
Haven't you ever had
?a very special friend
你有没有过
？一个非常特别的朋友
.Nickel Buddy-
.镍好友-
.I'll never spend you
.我永远不会花掉你
.Funny Muffler-
.有趣的消声器-
.Jerky Pal-
.肉干帕尔-
.Booboo Keys-
.Snake Eyes-
.蛇眼-
!We love you-
！我们爱你-
?So, what do you say-
？那么，你说什么-
!Pop the bubble-
！戳破泡泡——
!Pop the bubble
！戳破泡泡
Let's get this over-
with so I can go home
让我们结束这一切吧——
这样我就可以回家了
!and play my clarinet
！并演奏我的单簧管
--Nooo-
--不-
--ooo
--哦哦
!Whoa-
！哇-
[GASPS]
[喘气]
?Hey, don't I get a say in this
？嘿，我对此没有发言权吗？
.I'll see you later, SpongeBob
.稍后再见，海绵宝宝
Things are getting a
.little weird around here
事情正在变得
.这里有点奇怪
.So long-
。这么久-
!Happy Leif Erikson Day-
！莱夫·埃里克森日快乐-
.He's alive-
.他还活着-
.Of course-
。当然-
Otherwise he couldn't
.tell such funny jokes
否则他不能
.讲这么有趣的笑话
!Ha
！哈
[MUMBLING]
[咕哝]
.OK by me-
.我同意-
.I'm done
。我受够了
Seems like only this-
.morning I held his bottle
好像只有这个——
.早上我拿着他的瓶子
.They blow up so fast
.他们爆炸得如此之快
?Uh-- hi-
？呃--嗨-
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[主题音乐播放]